Simon Hudson

Front End Developer

www.hellosimonhudson.com / hellosimonhudson@gmail.com

I am an experienced Front End Developer who uses HTML, CSS and JavaScript to create accessible and usable websites and applications. I've been working in web development since 2004, and in that time I have worked on a wide range of projects, from small brochure-ware microsites through to enterprise-level single-page web apps serving millions of users. I am passionate about web accessibility and how to build for assistive technologies. I'm also a big fan of test-driven development, clean code, and striving for simple solutions to complex problems.

Core skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, web accessibility, Typescript, React, Sass, Node.js, Next.js, Express, Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library, Mocha, Chai, Nightwatch

Experience

Product Developer – Experian Consumer Services

May 2014 - present

Initially working on the front-end re-build of pages for users who had subscribed to Experian's monthly membership, I was part of a team who first introduced the concepts of progressive enhancement, graceful degradation and mobile-first, adaptive design to the development team and wider organisation. More recently I've been working on the company's Marketplace product (https://creditmatcher.experian.co.uk), helping to build the product from the ground up and iterate on it to regularly drive improvement over the last 6 years.

Responsibilities

- Writing lean, DRY code using a variety of languages/tools (Swig, Handlebars, Sass, Node, Express, React)
- Ensuring all code has associated unit tests which pass a minimum coverage threshold, using Jest, Enzyme, Chai and Mocha.
- As a long-standing member of the team, I've acted as a mentor/buddy to new starters and graduates.
- Liaise with wider team to review and refine requirements, provide point-based estimates, and plan work into fortnightly sprints.
- Actively driven accessibility standards amongst not only my team, but other workstreams in the organisation. Worked to ensure that accessibility considerations are "pulled left" as much as possible, liaising with Product and Design teams to review proposals and designs for any possible issues. Introduced accessibility automation tests using Cucumber and Nightwatch, which are run prior to any Production deployment.
- Acted as Security Champion for the team, requiring me to proactively review scans from tooling such as Veracode and Aquasec, and to raise tickets where necessary. Also acted as a point-of-contact on the team for any security issues.

Senior Front-end Developer - 4energy

July 2013 - May 2014

My role at 4energy was to act as the lead front-end developer amongst a team of back-end developers, working on monitoring software for data centre cooling systems. Originally built on a PHP/MySQL platform, the system was migrated over to Java and made heavy use of the Kendo UI library and Apache Velocity templating language, as well as Sass for CSS and HTML5 to optimise the interface across various devices and platforms.

Front-end Developer – NHS Choices (Capita)

May 2009 – Jan 2010 / April 2010 – July 2013

Working on one of the largest websites in Europe (https://www.nhs.uk/), it was my responsibility to create front-end code to the highest standards and then liaise with the back-end developers to ensure it was integrated properly into the solution. As a public health information site, accessibility was at the forefront of everything we did, and we had regular contact with third parties, such as the R.N.I.B and AbilityNet and acted based on their recommendations and audits.

Senior Web Designer – Manheim Europe

October 2006 - May 2009

I worked on a range of projects from small banner adverts and HTML e-mails, through to designing and implementing a group-wide intranet based on Drupal CMS, as well as designing and building websites for the company's operations in continental Europe. I also worked on large projects for high-profile clients such as BMW, Toyota and Daimler Chrysler, as well as performing day-to-day maintenance on the various Manheim websites. As Senior Designer, I assisted the Design Manager in the running of the department and acted as the main point-of-contact in his absence.

Graphic Designer/Web Developer (P/T) – University of Derby Students Union

November 2004 – September 2006

Working part-time during my studies, this role offered me the chance to gain real-world experience whilst studying. I assisted the lead designer in all aspects of Union marketing, from booklets and posters for events, through to maintenance of the Union website and contributing to the award-winning monthly student magazine. I was also given the responsibility of re-designing, building and launching the microsite for the Union's satellite campus in Buxton.

Education

University of Derby (2004 – 2006)

Foundation Degree in New Media Design & Production (Pass with Merit)

Derby College (1997 - 1999)

A Level English (Language & Literature), Psychology, Media Studies

Chellaston Secondary School, Derby (1992–1997)

9 G.C.S.E Higher Grade passes

References

Available on request